<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>solo travel on Blog</title>
    <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/tags/solo-travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in solo travel on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/tags/solo-travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Last Days</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/2019-1-3-last-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/2019-1-3-last-days/</guid>
      <description>How fast eighteen days can go by is unbelievable. This trip has been really awesome for me: I&amp;rsquo;ve seen new parts of the world and experienced new cultures, got to meet really cool people from all over the globe, and gained important knowledge for future solo travels. But first, Vienna and Salzburg.
I spent yesterday roaming around Vienna and then heading over to Schonbrunn Palace, the old seat of the Austrian Empire. The palace and gardens were impressive &amp;ndash; comparable to Versailles. The audio-guided tour of the inside was a little underwhelming, but I did learn that Schonbrunn played host to a meeting between Kennedy and Kruschev.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krakow and Budapest</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/2019-1-1-krakow-and-budapest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/2019-1-1-krakow-and-budapest/</guid>
      <description>Another week has already gone by! It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how fast the time goes &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ll be back at school this time next week. It was a snowy Christmas in Krakow, and pretty much the whole city was closed down. Wawel Castle was a highlight &amp;ndash; a really old castle with great views out over the city. Kazimierz, the Jewish Quarter, home of a circuit of old synagogues that survived the War, was also interesting. Our walking tour guide said that Kazimierz was populated with criminals after the War and was the seedy area of the city at the time, but has since become Krakow&amp;rsquo;s nightlife hub, playing gist to hundreds of bars and restaurants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prague, Olomouc, and Auschwitz</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/2021-01-02-prague-olomouc-and-auschwitz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/2021-01-02-prague-olomouc-and-auschwitz/</guid>
      <description>I have 20 minutes before my bus from Auschwitz to Krakow leaves, so I figured I have time to write another post!
I took a train from Vienna to Prague a few days ago to meet up with a friend who was doing abroad there. I slept through most of the ride, so I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to say on that other than that the Czech countryside &amp;ndash; or the parts of it that I saw, at least &amp;ndash; were very pretty. Rolling hills, light dusting of snow, lots of trees and streams, etc. I roamed around for a little bit in Prague before meeting up with my friend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Days -- ZRH and Vienna</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/2021-01-02-first-days-zrh-and-vienna/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/2021-01-02-first-days-zrh-and-vienna/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s 5:43AM in Vienna, and I can&amp;rsquo;t sleep. Jet lag. So far, so good on my trip. The flight here went surprisingly well &amp;ndash; I woke up and was about an hour from landing in Zurich, which was unexpected and much appreciated. Flying in and out of ZRH was just about all I could ask for in a connection. The views of the Alps and snow-dusted cities and towns from the air are unbelievable. ZRH lived up to its (Swiss) reputation: clean, well-organized, easy to navigate, and overall very efficient. One weird thing about the flight in, though: we didn&amp;rsquo;t fill out immigration cards on the flight in to Zurich from JFK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solo Trip to Europe in December, 2018</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/2021-01-02-solo-trip-to-europe-in-december-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/2021-01-02-solo-trip-to-europe-in-december-2018/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to Europe in a few weeks! I&amp;rsquo;m flying into Vienna, and then am heading to Prague, Olomouc, Krakow, Budapest, and Salzburg. I&amp;rsquo;ll be staying in hostels all along the way, and could not be more excited. This is my first real solo trip (something I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to do for a while), so it should be a great experience. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to post updates along the way of what I&amp;rsquo;m seeing and doing, but I&amp;rsquo;m not totally sure whether or not I will bring my computer. If not, I&amp;rsquo;m definitely going to write a trip update when I get back stateside.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
