<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My blog</title>
    <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Our 2021 Big Data Bowl Submission</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/our-2021-big-data-bowl-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/our-2021-big-data-bowl-submission/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Our project aims to measure the ability of defensive backs at performing different aspects of their defensive duties: deterring targets (either by reputation or through good positioning), closing down receivers, and breaking up passes. We do this by fitting four models, two for predicting the probability that a receiver will be targeted on a given play and two for predicting the probability that a pass will be caught, which we then use to aggregate the contributions of defensive backs over the course of the season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host Family Q&amp;A</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/host-family-q-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/host-family-q-a/</guid>
      <description>This is a blog post Q&amp;amp;A I wrote for the Swedish Program blog. You can find the original post here.
Housing is a big part of your study abroad experience. At The Swedish Program, we offer students the choice of an apartment or host family, both of which provide opportunities for cultural integration. It can be tough to decide which option is right for you, so we asked Fall 2019 student Matt Kaye (Carleton College ‘19) to describe his experience living with a host family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Weeks in Stockholm</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/first-weeks-in-stockholm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/first-weeks-in-stockholm/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m now finishing up my third week in Stockholm &amp;ndash; time flies. Week 1 was mostly orientation: learning a little bit of Swedish, meeting the other group members, starting to find our way around the city, etc. We trekked out to Sandhamn, an island in the Archipelago, for the first weekend. Really beautiful spot. Weeks 2 and 3 were the start of classes &amp;ndash; 3 program classes and 1 SSE class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Days</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/last-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/last-days/</guid>
      <description>How fast eighteen days can go by is unbelievable. This trip has been really awesome for me: I&amp;rsquo;ve seen new parts of the world and experienced new cultures, got to meet really cool people from all over the globe, and gained important knowledge for future solo travels. But first, Vienna and Salzburg.
I spent yesterday roaming around Vienna and then heading over to Schonbrunn Palace, the old seat of the Austrian Empire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krakow and Budapest</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/krakow-and-budapest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/krakow-and-budapest/</guid>
      <description>Another week has already gone by! It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how fast the time goes &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ll be back at school this time next week. It was a snowy Christmas in Krakow, and pretty much the whole city was closed down. Wawel Castle was a highlight &amp;ndash; a really old castle with great views out over the city. Kazimierz, the Jewish Quarter, home of a circuit of old synagogues that survived the War, was also interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prague, Olomouc, and Auschwitz</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/prague-olomouc-and-auschwitz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/prague-olomouc-and-auschwitz/</guid>
      <description>I have 20 minutes before my bus from Auschwitz to Krakow leaves, so I figured I have time to write another post!
I took a train from Vienna to Prague a few days ago to meet up with a friend who was doing abroad there. I slept through most of the ride, so I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to say on that other than that the Czech countryside &amp;ndash; or the parts of it that I saw, at least &amp;ndash; were very pretty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Days -- ZRH and Vienna</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/first-days-zrh-and-vienna/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/first-days-zrh-and-vienna/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s 5:43AM in Vienna, and I can&amp;rsquo;t sleep. Jet lag. So far, so good on my trip. The flight here went surprisingly well &amp;ndash; I woke up and was about an hour from landing in Zurich, which was unexpected and much appreciated. Flying in and out of ZRH was just about all I could ask for in a connection. The views of the Alps and snow-dusted cities and towns from the air are unbelievable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solo Trip to Europe in December, 2018</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/solo-trip-to-europe-in-december-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/solo-trip-to-europe-in-december-2018/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to Europe in a few weeks! I&amp;rsquo;m flying into Vienna, and then am heading to Prague, Olomouc, Krakow, Budapest, and Salzburg. I&amp;rsquo;ll be staying in hostels all along the way, and could not be more excited. This is my first real solo trip (something I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to do for a while), so it should be a great experience. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to post updates along the way of what I&amp;rsquo;m seeing and doing, but I&amp;rsquo;m not totally sure whether or not I will bring my computer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
