<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data science on Musings</title>
    <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data science on Musings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why I Write R, and Why You Should Too</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/2021-01-14-why-i-write-r-and-why-you-should-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/2021-01-14-why-i-write-r-and-why-you-should-too/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I write R all the time. All of my work is done in R (yes, that includes productionizing models), I write R for fun, I maintain an R package and am the author of another, and I wrote this post in R Markdown. But, why? If you peruse blogs on Towards Data Science or r/datascience, you&amp;rsquo;ll find person after person telling new data scientists or data scientists-in-training to learn python instead of R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Gentle Introduction to Markov Chains and MCMC</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/2021-01-13-a-gentle-introduction-to-markov-chains-and-mcmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/2021-01-13-a-gentle-introduction-to-markov-chains-and-mcmc/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Every other Friday at work, we have a meeting called All Hands, during the first half of which a member of the team gives a presentation. The presentation is split up into two pieces: A personal presentation &amp;ndash; your favorite food, TV shows, books, etc. &amp;ndash; and a mini-lesson, which can be about any topic of interest that&amp;rsquo;s unrelated to work. Yesterday it was my turn, and I gave my mini-lesson on Markov Chains and Markov Chain Monte Carlo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our 2021 Big Data Bowl Submission</title>
      <link>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/our-2021-big-data-bowl-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrkaye97.github.io/blog/post/our-2021-big-data-bowl-submission/</guid>
      <description>Meta This post is my team&amp;rsquo;s 2021 NFL Big Data Bowl submission. My team was made up of me, Hugh McCreery (Baltimore Orioles), John Edwards (Seattle Mariners), and Owen McGrattan (DS student at Berkeley). I&amp;rsquo;m proud of what we&amp;rsquo;ve put forth here, and hopefully you find it interesting. At the end (after the Appendix), I&amp;rsquo;ve added some overall thoughs on things we were curious about or feel like we could have done better, as well as what we view as the biggest strengths and weaknesses of our submission.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
